<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Monumental!</string>

    <string-array name="world_wonders">
        <item>Alhambra</item>
        <item>Angkor Wat</item>
        <item>Big Ben</item>
        <item>Bolshoi Theatre</item>
        <item>Borobudur</item>
        <item>Brandenburg Gate</item>
        <item>Broadway</item>
        <item>Casa de Contratación</item>
        <item>Chichen Itza</item>
        <item>The Colosseum</item>
        <item>Christo Redentor</item>
        <item>Eiffel Tower</item>
        <item>Forbidden City</item>
        <item>Golden Gate Bridge</item>
        <item>The Great Wall</item>
        <item>Hagia Sophia</item>
        <item>Hermitage</item>
        <item>Kotoku-In</item>
        <item>The Louvre</item>
        <item>Machu Picchu</item>
        <item>Mahabodhi Temple</item>
        <item>Meenakshi Temple</item>
        <item>Mont. St. Michel</item>
        <item>Notre Dame</item>
        <item>Országház</item>
        <item>The Parthenon</item>
        <item>Petra</item>
        <item>Poatala Palace</item>
        <item>The Pyramids</item>
        <item>St. Basil Cathedral</item>
        <item>Statue of Liberty</item>
        <item>Stonehenge</item>
        <item>Sydney Opera House</item>
        <item>Taj Mahal</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="world_wonders_quote">
        <item>\"Everything here appears calculated to inspire kind and happy feelings, for everything is delicate and beautiful\" \n\n -Washington Irving</item>
        <item>\"The temple is like no other building in the world. It has towers and decoration and all the refinements which the human genius can conceive of.\" \n\n– Antonio da Magdalena </item>
        <item>\"Don’t watch the big clock; do what it does. Keep going.\" \n\n– Sam Levenson</item>
        <item>\"Bolshoi Ballet is a universe of the imagination, a place of magic and enchantment, beauty and romance. Its many worlds vibrate with graceful dancers, glorious music, and sumptuous costumes.\" \n\n– Trudy Garfunkel</item>
        <item>\"When you realize how perfect everything is, you will tilt your head back and laugh at the sky.\" \n\n– Gautama Buddha</item>
        <item>\"Pale Death beats equally at the poor man\'s gate and at the palaces of kings.\" \n\n – Horace</item>
        <item>\"Broadway is a main artery of New York cultural life - the hardened artery.\" \n\n– Walter Winchell</item>
        <item>\"All other lands found on the western side of the boundary shall belong to the King and Queen of Castille—and their successors.\" \n\n– Treaty of Tordesillas </item>
        <item>\"The katun is established at Chichen Itza. The settlement of the Itza shall take place there. The quetzal shall come, the green bird shall come. Ah Kantenal shall come. It is the word of God. The Itza shall come.\" \n\n– The Books of Chilam Balam</item>
        <item>\"While the Colosseum stands, Rome shall stand; when the Colosseum falls, Rome shall fall; when Rome falls, the world shall fall.\" \n\n – Saint Bede</item>
        <item>\"Thus, the sculpture serves to give people one thought - Everything is in God\'s hands.\" \n\n– Sergey Semenov</item>
        <item>\"We live only to discover beauty, all else is a form of waiting\" \n\n– Kahlil Gibran</item>
        <item>\"Most of us can, as we choose, make of this world either a palace or a prison.\" \n\n – John Lubbock</item>
        <item>\"The Golden Gate of Sleep unbar \nWhere Strength and Beauty, met together,\nKindle their image like a star\nIn a sea of glassy weather!\" \n\n– Percy Bysshe Shelley</item>
        <item>\"The art of war teaches us to rely not on the likelihood of the enemy\'s not attacking, but rather on the fact that we have made our position unassailable.\" \n\n – Sun Tzu</item>
        <item>\"For it soars to a height to match the sky, and as if surging up from among the other buildings it stands on high and looks down upon the remainder of the city, adorning it, because it is a part of it, but glorying in its own beauty.\" \n\n– Procopius, De Aedificis </item>
        <item>\"Museums are on the front lines of the fight for culture, of good with evil - in any case, of the fight against platitudes and primitiveness.\" \n\n – Mikhail Piotrovsky, Director of the State Hermitage</item>
        <item>\"O ye who tread the Narrow Way, by Tophet-flare to Judgment Day, be gentle when \‘the heathen\’ pray, to Buddha at Kamakura!\" \n\n – Rudyard Kipling</item>
        <item>\"Every genuine work of art has as much reason for being as the earth and the sun.\" \n\n– Ralph Waldo Emerson</item>
        <item>\"Few romances can ever surpass that of the granite citadel on top of the beetling precipices of Machu Picchu, the crown of Inca Land.\" \n\n– Hiram Bingham</item>
        <item>\"In a dusty, bustling corner of the Indian state of Bihar, there is a magical place that one might think of as the hub of Buddhism.\" \n\n- Visitor\'s Guide, Bodh Gaya</item>
        <item>\"We greet you, Devi Meenakshi, she who shines like a thousand-million suns, adorned with bracelets and garlands... She who is auspicious, she who embodies existence. I always bow to you, whose compassion is an ocean.\" \n\n– Adi Shankara</item>
        <item>\"Church and State, Soul and Body, God and Man, are all one at Mont Saint Michel, and the business of all is to fight, each in his own way, or to stand guard for each other.\" \n\n – Henry Adams</item>
        <item>\"Architecture has recorded the great ideas of the human race. Not only every religious symbol, but every human thought has its page in that vast book.\" \n\n- Victor Hugo </item>
        <item>\"With self-government is freedom, and with freedom is justice and patriotism.\" \n\n – Lajos Kossuth</item>
        <item>\"Earth proudly wears the Parthenon as the best gem upon her zone.\" \n\n– Ralph Waldo Emerson </item>
        <item>\"Petra is a brilliant display of man\'s artistry in turning barren rock into majestic wonder.\" \n\n– Edward Dawson</item>
        <item>\"The first time I stepped onto the rooftop of the Potala Palace, I felt, as never before or since, as if I were stepping onto the rooftop of my being: onto some dimension of consciousness that I’d never visited before.\" \n\n– Pico Iyer</item>
        <item>\"From the heights of these pyramids, forty centuries look down on us.\" \n\n– Napoleon Bonaparte </item>
        <item>\"One had a twisted design, red, on a green ground; another, all prickly angles, yellow and black; a third was ornamented with scales of blue and crimson; a [fourth] was in quarters like a melon.\" \n\n – Katharine Blanche Guthrie</item>
        <item>\"Give me your tired, your poor, your huddled masses yearning to breathe free, the wretched refuse of your teeming shore. Send these, the homeless, tempest-tossed to me, I lift my lamp beside the golden door!\" \n\n– Emma Lazarus
 </item>
        <item>\"Time crumbles things; everything grows old and is forgotten under the power of time\" \n\n– Aristotle
 </item>
        <item>\"An opera begins long before the curtain goes up and ends long after it has come down. It starts in my imagination, it becomes my life, and it stays part of my life long after I\'ve left the opera house.\" \n\n– Maria Callas </item>
        <item>\"The Taj Mahal rises above the banks of the river like a solitary tear suspended on the cheek of time.\" \n\n– Rabindranath Tagore </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="world_wonders_desc">
        <item>Found in southern Spain, the Alhambra is a large palace complex of the Nasrid Dynasty, who controlled the region in the mid 14th century. Construction began sometime around 1238 AD under the rule of Ibn al-Hamar, and continued under his successors. Taking its name from the red hue of its walls, the name Alhambra is translated as the \"Red Fortress\". It integrated the natural beauty of the spot, with structures and gardens designed and outfitted by the finest Muslim, Jewish and even Christian craftsmen and artisans of the region.</item>
        <item>It has stood for nearly 1,000 years, a monument to a god and possibly the final resting place of the conqueror king who built it.\n\nAnd still, the temple at Angkor Wat endures, its central tower rising 213 feet above the surrounding jungle. Constructed by the Khmer King Suryavarman II in the Twelfth century in what is now northern Cambodia, it is one of the world\'s tallest religious monuments.\n\nA pilgrim to the city-temple of the Hindu God Vishnu would first cross a 650-foot wide and 14-feet deep moat surrounding the structure before entering a \'gopura,\' a three-towered entrance leading to a raised walkway. Inside the temple complex proper, they would find four smaller towers surrounding one central 213-foot tower, evoking the sacred Mount Meru.\n\nKhmer Shaivist temples typically face east, but because Angkor Wat faces west, the final resting place for Suryavarman\'s remains would be a temple honoring Vishnu.</item>
        <item>\The giant bell, Big Ben, is housed in the Elizabeth Tower – so named to celebrate the Diamond Jubilee of Queen Elizabeth II (being just the “Clock Tower” before that) – at the north end of the Palace of Westminster, where sits the Houses of Parliament. Being rather casual in language, most Brits and flocks of tourists tend to refer to the whole thing as “Big Ben.” The great 16-ton bell was cast in August 1856 at the foundry at Stockton-on-Tees and recast at the Whitechapel Bell Foundry in April 1858 after it cracked while being transported to London. The pendulum clockwork was designed by the Astronomer Royal and crafted by the clockmaker Edward Dent and his stepson Frederick; it was ready in 1854. So fine is the precision, that adding or removing a penny (English, of course) to the pendulum will change the speed by four-tenths of a second each day. But all had to await the completion of the clock tower itself, which wasn’t done until 1859. Despite being silenced during wartime and the occasional breakdown, Big Ben has chimed the hour ever since.\</item>
        <item>\The Imperial Bolshoi Theatre of Moscow – bolshoi being the Russian for “grand” – is home for the Bolshoi Ballet and Bolshoi Opera companies, among the oldest and largest in the world (the ballet has some 200 dancers). The ballet company was founded in March 1776 by Prince Urusov and Michael Maddox, a British theater manager; after performing in private homes for some years, the company was profitable enough to acquire the Petrovka Theater and opened there for the first time in December 1780. Sadly, the Petrovka burned down in 1805, to be replaced by the New Arbat Theater, which burned down in 1812 during Napoleon’s occupation of the city. The current Bolshoi Theater was built between 1821 and 1824, and it managed not to burn down – although it was renovated in 1843, 1856, 1921, 2002 and 2011. The last renovation included restoring the theater’s acoustics to the original high quality (which had been mucked up by the Soviets) and restoring the original imperial décor (which had been ripped out by those same Soviets).\</item>
        <item>\Borobudur is a Buddhist candi in Magelang, Java, consisting of six square platforms surmounted by three circular platforms, atop which are 72 small stupas surrounding a large central stupa. The structure is decorated with 2672 bas-relief carvings and 504 Buddhist statues. The temple\'s three levels represent the three realms of Buddhist cosmology: the world of desires, the world of forms, and the formless world. Construction of Borobudur was completed at some point between 778 and 850 AD, during the Sailendra dynasty. Around 1006 the nearby capital of the successor Medang Kingdom was abandoned due to a series of volcanic eruptions; pilgrimages to Borobudur ceased shortly thereafter. The temple was lost for centuries under layers of ash and jungle until discovered by the British lieutenant governor of Java, Sir Stamford Raffles, in 1814.\</item>
        <item>\The Brandenburg Gate is the only surviving town gate of the city of Berlin. A beautiful "triumphal arch" constructed in the Greek style in 1788-91, it features many columns and is surmounted by the "Quadriga of Victory," a statue of a chariot drawn by four horses. It stands at the end of the avenue Unter den Linden.\n\nAfter World War II, Berlin was partitioned between sections controlled by the Soviet Union, and the United States and its allies. The Berlin Wall was constructed by the Soviets to keep the two parts of the city separated. The Brandenburg Gate was in a sort of a "no-man\'s land" between the two factions, and from 1961-1989 neither side had access. The Gate was reopened in 1989 as part of the reunification of Berlin and Germany.\n\nToday it stands as a proud symbol of the reunified city and country, and it is visited by tens of thousands of tourists from both east and west.\</item>
        <item>\Broadway is a 15-mile long thoroughfare through the heart of Manhattan and the Bronx in New York City, lined with offices, shops and apartments … but no-one thinks of those. Instead, Broadway is best known for the middle section between 42nd and 53rd Streets dubbed the “Great White Way” – the Theater District. Commencing in the mid-1800s a number of theaters opened on Broadway. In 1880 AD a stretch between Madison and Union squares was illuminated with arc lamps, making it one of the first electrically lit streets in the United States (leave it to New Yorkers to light up theaters before homes, hospitals and schools). Spurred by growing American wealth and cultural aspirations, the theaters made it a mecca of popular entertainment. By 1900 some 20 theaters had opened along this stretch, and so bright were their electric billboards that it became the Great White Way. In 1925 at its peak popularity, there were 80 theaters along Broadway, specializing in lavish productions, primarily revues and musicals.\</item>
        <item>\When Spain joined the late 15th Century’s exploration race, Queen Isabella I of Castile and Ferdinand II of Aragón realized they needed a firmer grasp on colonial trade and expansion. Through their Casa de Contratación, a “House of Trade” created to regulate trade and procurement, the Spanish crown controlled everything related to trade and sea travel down to the smallest details. Even their navigation and cartography school kept literal trade secrets in house.\n\nSeville was home to the first incarnation of the Casa de Contración, but the agency moved to Cádiz in 1717. Moving to a city near the southern tip of Spain streamlined the influx of ships, which had previously traveled up the highly trafficked Guadalquivir River. The Casa remained in Cádiz until its termination in 1790 due to the empire’s growing debts.\</item>
        <item>\Chichen Itza is an extraordinary city of stone built in the Yucatán, Mexico. Some of the oldest buildings and pyramids date back to 1500 years ago and are of Toltec and Mayan origin.\n\nChichen Itza consists of buildings, temples and courtyards of stone. A large "pok tap ok" or ceremonial ball court stands off to one side. (Ceremonial ball is that most interesting of games in which two sides sought to pass the ball through hoops at each end of the court. The captain of the winning team was then beheaded as a sacrifice to the gods.) Though the city is much ravaged by time (and looters), there still remain many beautiful stone carvings and statues.\n\nAt the center of the city stands the mighty stepped pyramid of Kukulcan, also known as "El Castillo." Constructed around the 13th century, El Castillo is approximately 17 meters square (180 feet square) at the base and 24 m (78 feet) in height. As was the Mayan practice, Kukulcan was constructed atop an older and smaller pyramid.\n\nChichen Itza was a thriving city until the 13th century, when revolt and civil war broke out among the Mayans, at which point the city went into a steep decline from which it never recovered. The center of the city was largely abandoned and in ruins by the time of the Spanish Conquest of the Yucatán in the 16th century.\</item>
        <item>\The Flavian Amphitheater, better known as the “Coliseum” lies in the center of Rome. Construction began during the reign of Emperor Vespasian, c. 72 AD, funded by the spoils from the Jewish Second Temple after the fall of Jerusalem during the First Jewish-Roman War. Built of concrete and stone, it is the largest amphitheater ever built, and one of the great wonders of ancient architecture and engineering. It could hold between 50 and 80 thousand spectators to watch gladiatorial matches, animal hunts, mass executions, and more.\n\nBy the time medieval Christianity had taken root, it had been repurposed to house low-rent apartments, workshops, quarters for a religious order, a quarry and a Christian shrine. Although knocked about by earthquakes and pillaged by stone-robbers, the Coliseum is still pretty impressive two millennia after the inaugural gladiatorial slaughter.\</item>
        <item>\The largest art deco statue in the world, Cristo Redentor (“Christ the Redeemer”) stands atop Corcovado Mountain 2300 feet above Rio de Janeiro, keeping a watchful eye on the sinners of that city. With arms spread wide to embrace the city sprawling below in spectacular disorder, this statue of Christ stands 98 feet tall, with the arms measuring 92 feet from fingertip to fingertip. It was sculpted by the Frenchman Paul Landowski, and built of reinforced concrete and soapstone.\n\nThe idea of putting a giant statue of Christ above the city was first proposed by the Catholic priest Pedro Boss; proposed again in 1920 by the “Catholic Circle” of Rio, the group raised the necessary funds from donations, mostly from devout Brazilian Catholics (of course). Construction began in 1922, and the monument opened to the public in October 1931.\</item>
        <item>\The Eiffel Tower is one of the world\'s most famous landmarks. Built for the Universal Exposition of 1889, the tower rises 300 meters (984 feet) above Paris\' Champ de Mars, near the Seine River. Structural engineer Alexandre Gustave Eiffel built the tower to demonstrate how steel and iron could be utilized in the construction of extremely tall buildings. The cost was more than $1 million.\n\nThe tallest building in the world when it was originally completed, the Eiffel Tower drew crowds of awestruck observers from around the world. Today, it remains one of Paris\' leading tourist attractions.\</item>
        <item>\Lying in the center of Beijing, a visit to Gu Gong (the Imperial Palace of China) was forbidden to the common folk without special dispensation from the emperor himself; hence the complex became known across the land as the “Forbidden City” (much like most presidential residences these days).\n\nConstruction of the walled “city” – liberally sprinkled with ornamental gardens, graceful terraces, restful fountains and lots of utilitarian administrative offices – began in 1408 AD under the guidance of the Yonglu Emperor, third of the Ming dynasty.\n\nThe complex grew over the centuries, serving as home to 24 emperors of the Ming and Qing. It grew until it encompassed 9,999 rooms spread over 178 square acres, surrounded by a 170-foot wide moat and 32-foot high walls (just to make sure none of those commoners entered unchecked). At its peak, the Forbidden City was home to ten thousand people, all to serve the needs of one emperor.\</item>
        <item>\Nestled in the San Francisco fog is the iconic Golden Gate Bridge, a 1.7 mile long suspension bridge that defied everything believed to be true about engineering when it was completed in 1937. Spanning across the Golden Gate Strait, this wonder of the modern world connects San Francisco to northern California counties, providing a necessary commuter route and unnecessary traffic for residents and visitors alike.\n\nThough its name suggests the color of its beams, the bridge is actually painted International Orange. Although this wasn\'t the original intended color for the project – black and yellow stripes were the leading choice – it complemented the landscape and gave the bridge some much needed visibility in the fog. So much visibility that it is believed to be the most photographed bridge in the world, and has made its mark on pop culture in movies, television, and video games.\</item>
        <item>\The Great Wall of China is one of the largest and most famous man-made constructions in the entire world. Chinese rulers built the Great Wall to ward off attack from nomadic tribesmen living in modern Manchuria and Mongolia. Interestingly, the Great Wall was not designed to keep the nomads out - the Chinese knew it was all but impossible to defend such a long border - it was designed to make it difficult for the raiders to carry off loot, thus making raids far less profitable and thus less worth the risks involved.\n\nThere have actually been five different "Great Walls" built by different Chinese dynasties. The first four were constructed of earth and have since all but disappeared. The current wall was built almost entirely by the Ming Dynasty between 1368 and 1640 AD.\n\nThis wall was constructed on a grander scale, using more permanent materials (like stone). The Ming wall stretches for 6,354 km (3,948 miles) from Shanhai Pass on the Bohai Gulf in the east to Lop Nur in the southeast portion of Xinjiang\'s Uygur Autonomous Region in the west.This was the region where the Silk Road first entered China, and a series of watchtowers which could communicate via smoke signals were intended to pass messages rapidly along the wall\'s vast length.\</item>
        <item>\The Hagia Sophia, or "High Wisdom," was constructed in 530 AD as a Greek Orthodox church. It has been in service, most as a place of worship, for almost 1500 years. It is a remarkable building as it has survived many earthquakes, sometimes needing large repairs. It is a beautiful and ornate structure, built of stone and marble, and topped by a golden dome measuring over 30 m (100 feet) in diameter. An extremely difficult engineering challenge for the time, the dome has collapsed several times during its existence. Later on the Ottomans added 4 minarets, marking it one of the important mosques of the world.\n\nThe classical interior of the Hagia Sophia is a marvelous space of columns and arches extending up to the dome, which appears almost to float atop the building. It breathes the classical age, nowhere else left to be found. The interior was sheathed in colored marble and golden mosaics depicting biblical scenes and images of Christian saints.\n\nIn 1453 Constantinople was captured by the Ottoman Turks, and the Hagia Sophia was converted into a mosque. Human images are not welcome in mosques, and many of the mosaics were covered with plaster. In 1934, Turkish President Kemal Atatürk turned the building into a museum. In recent years some restoration work has been done on the Hagia Sophia, and a few of the mosaics have been uncovered. Despite the ravages of time, the Hagia Sophia remains universally acknowledged as one of the most beautiful buildings in the world.\</item>
        <item>\The core of what is today the famed Hermitage in St. Petersburg encompasses the monumental Winter Palace, residence of the Tsars since 1764 AD when Catherine the Great completed the palace on a scale to reflect the might and power of Imperial Russia. Catherine declared it her “treasure,” and proceeded to fill it with treasures – Renaissance paintings, jeweled and gilded crafts (the likes of Fabergé eggs, for instance), the crown jewels, and other trinkets. After adding several extensions to the palace and some reorganizing, in 1852 Nicholas I opened it to the public. And the Tsars kept adding to the collection.\n\nWith the February Revolution of 1917, the building briefly housed the Provisional Government, until the Bolsheviks seized power in October and declared it a gift to the proletariat. Now spread across five buildings, the Hermitage is one of the largest museums in the world, with over three million art and historical items in its collection, including the largest gathering of paintings in the world.\</item>
        <item>\Serene, enduring, and somewhat mysterious, the Buddha statue known as the Daibutsu sits outside of Kamakura’s Kōtoku-in. Towering over the Buddhist temple’s visitors, the Daibutsu patiently greets both faithful and tourist alike. An unknown artist cast the Great Buddha of Kamakura out of bronze, which has since oxidized into a muted green color through natural weathering.\n\nHowever, the Kōtoku-in’s artist clearly built it to last. It survived an earthquake and two typhoons, one of which destroyed the building that used to surround it. The statue remains unfazed by nature’s attempts to unseat its 750-year meditation.\</item>
        <item>\The Louvre is a large and incredibly ornate palace in Paris, France. Originally constructed in the 15th century on the site of an even older castle, for the next two and a half centuries the Louvre served as the home to many of France\'s kings, most of whom added to the already-huge structure.\n\nDuring the 17th century Kings Louis XIII and Louis XIV and their advisors Cardinals Richelieu and Mazarin began acquiring an extensive art collection which was kept at the Louvre.\n\nIn 1682 the Royal court moved to Versailles, and in 1793 the Revolutionary government opened the palace to the public. It has remained a public museum ever since. Not surprisingly, it is considered to have the finest collection of pre-modern French paintings in the world.\</item>
        <item>\Clinging to a Peruvian mountaintop at an elevation of 2,350 m (7,700 feet), Machu Picchu was an extraordinary Incan city and a marvel of pre-Columbian architecture. Constructed in the mid-15th century, scholars believe that much of the city was a palace complex of the mighty Incan ruler Pachacuti Inca Yupanqui. Constructed almost entirely of white granite stone, the city was inexplicably deserted in the mid-16th century. The marauding Spanish Conquistadors did not discover the site during their conquest of the Incas, so it has remained relatively intact until today.\n\nArchaeologists have identified the aforementioned palace complex, as well as temples, residential areas, plazas and a cemetery, all carved from the living rock. The mountainous terrain surrounding the central structures has been carved into stepped agricultural terraces which were at one time watered by an extensive aqueduct system, in itself a remarkable feat in a mountainous locale.\n\nAlthough in ruins, Machu Picchu retains an extraordinary rugged beauty even today. It must have been an incredible city during the days when the mighty Incas called it home.\</item>
        <item>\The Mahabodhi Temple (or “Great Awakening” Temple) in Bodh Gaya is one of the four sacred sites of the Lord Buddha’s (Siddhartha Gautama) life, and the very spot where he attained Enlightenment. On the western side of the temple is the sacred Bodhi Tree, the very fig tree under which the Buddha was sitting when he did so. Be all that as it may, the first Mahabodhi Temple (there have been a couple) was built by the Emperor Asoka c. 250 BC.\n\nThe current temple complex – notably the great tower, one of the first brick structures in India – dates from the 5th and 6th centuries AD. A high wall around the temple grounds was added at a later, undocumented, date; the wall encompasses the Bodhi Tree and six other sacred site of Buddha’s very enlightenment, since he spent seven weeks in seven different spots meditating on his very own revelations, as well as numerous Votive stupas.\n\nIn the 1880s the British Raj undertook a restoration effort; in 1949 control of the very site passed to the state government of Bihar. Today, Buddhists from the world over make pilgrimage to Bodh Gaya as the holiest place of their very faith.\</item>
        <item>\The Meenakshi Amman Temple dates back to the first century and is one of the oldest temples in India, still receiving thousands of visitors daily. Devoted to the goddess Meenakshi, a representation of love and fertility, this colorful complex spans 14 acres and is composed of tall walls, various shrines, 14 Gopurams (ornate gatehouse towers), and several Manapams (pillared halls).\n\nBrightly painted ceilings and stone carvings can be throughout the complex, but it is perhaps the thousands of vibrant stone statues lining the towers that have become most iconic. These small sculptures depict moments from Hindu stories – gods, demons, heroes, and animals. Every twelve years, these works are repainted and repaired.\</item>
        <item>\Perched on a rocky islet between Normandy and Brittany in the midst of sandbanks washed over by ocean tides, Mont St. Michel is a Gothic-style Benedictine abbey dedicated to the archangel Micheal built between the 11th and 16th centuries. Besides St. Aubert\'s skull, the Mont also was repository for bits of St. Petroc and St. Olaf and other holy relics.\n\nThe place did have a practical purpose; its high walls, turrets and position made it of strategic worth … and many a French king stationed a small garrison (all that was needed) there. At low tide, it was readily accessible to pilgrims eager to give up a coin or two to be blessed; at high tide, the incoming sea would strand or drown any attacking force.\n\nThe Mont would remain unconquered throughout the Hundred Years\' War and beyond. Its position also made it ideal to incarcerate unrepentant traitors and other sinners; Louis XI turned the Mont into a prison, a role it served through the rest of the Ancien Régime.\n\nNow, it\'s still an abbey hosting a religious community, as well as a highly touristic visited place.\</item>
        <item>\Notre Dame is a mighty cathedral standing on the "Île de la Cité," an island in the Seine River in Paris, France. Built on the site of an older church, which was in turn built on the site of a Roman temple to Jupiter, Notre Dame is a magnificent example of gothic architecture and one of the greatest buildings standing. Construction of Notre Dame began in 1163 and took almost two centuries to complete.\n\nNotre Dame is a massive stone building of square towers, flying buttresses, and tall spires. The exterior is decorated with delicate ribbons of arches and statues of saints and kings. The roofline of the building is festooned with gargoyles. The interior of the cathedral is a long, narrow space with columns lining each side, supporting two beautiful raised galleries. Brilliant stained glass windows shine gently down on the main altar, which contains a beautiful statue of the Virgin Mary, the cathedral\'s patron, holding the body of Jesus.\n\nThe cathedral has suffered many periods of neglect over the years. During the French Revolution, many of Notre Dame\'s treasures were stolen and the building was used as a warehouse. In the early 1800s, the cathedral was in such a state of disrepair that the city planners contemplated tearing it down. In fact, Victor Hugo wrote "The Hunchback of Notre Dame" in part to raise awareness of the cathedral\'s plight. In 1871, during the short-lived Paris Commune, Notre Dame was almost set on fire. Fortunately the cathedral survived it all, and has now been largely restored to its original grandeur.\</item>
        <item>\Orszaghaz translates to “House of the Country” but is better known as the Hungarian Parliament Building. This important building houses the members of Parliament, Hungarian Holy Crown, and the offices of the Prime Minister and staff.\n\nBut aside from its significance to the government of Hungary, this building itself is an impressive display of Gothic Revival architecture. Overlooking the Danube River, the long wing spans 268 meters, and it is the tallest building in Budapest. Two identical halls for the Lower and Upper houses of Parliament stretch beyond a tall, central dome. Decorating the exterior façade are 90 stone sculptures that portray great moments of Hungarian history, as well as ornately carved stone.\n\nIf that wasn\'t enough to excite visitors to this grand building, the precious stones and 88 lbs of gold used for decoration should do the trick.\</item>
        <item>\Built upon the Acropolis, dedicated to the goddess Athena, the Parthenon is considered the culmination of Doric architecture. Construction of the temple began in 447 BC; the last decorations were put into place in 432 BC and are important surviving examples of classical sculpture. It housed the chryselephantine statute of Athena sculpted by Phidius, and the outer facade was ornamented with 92 metopes. Like most Greek temples, the Parthenon also served as treasury, both for Athens itself and for the Delian League.\n\nThrough the 1700s, European tourists and scholars enjoyed greater access to the picturesque ruins and its fame spread. When Greece regained its independence in 1832, the government took control of the site.\n\nUndertaking a restoration of the Acropolis in 1975, Greece has made the Parthenon an enduring symbol of ancient Greece, Athenian democratic ideals, Western civilization and one of the world\'s greatest cultural treasures.\</item>
        <item>\Situated between the Red Sea and the Dead Sea, Petra is a city cut from the red sandstone around Wadi Musa (now part of Jordan) by the Nabataeans – who obviously had a lot of free time – around 400 BC. Mentioned in Egyptian, Greek and Biblical sources, the city would develop into a major caravan center, a vital crossroads between Arabia, Egypt and Syria to the north. Surrounded by mountains riddled with gorges and canyon passages, it was defensible; but it was the ingenious and extensive system of cisterns and reservoirs in the middle of a desert that made it a trade center.\n\nAt its peak, Petra was home to perhaps 20 thousand inhabitants, and served as the capital of the Nabataean kingdom. That is, until the Romans arrived and annexed it in 106 AD. Struck by a series of earthquakes, as well as Roman taxes, it was essentially abandoned two hundred years after – not to be “discovered” until 1812 by the Swiss explorer Johann Burckhardt.\</item>
        <item>\Since there wasn’t much level ground in Tibet, with its base set on the southern slope of the Red Hill, the Potala Palace – home to the Dalai Lama (until the fourteenth one fled an uprising in 1959) – sort of grew along the hillside.\n\nThe palace is named after Mount Potalaka, abode of the eleven-headed bodhisattva Avalokiteśvara. Today, its crimson and white walls and golden roof “shine in glory” … for paying tourists. Lozang Gyatso, the fifth Dalai Lama, began construction of the “modern” palace above Lhasa c. 1645 AD, and moved in four years later.\n\nSince then more bits and pieces have been added to the sprawling edifice, notably the Potrang Marpo (“red palace”) and the holy stupa completed in 1694. However, it should be noted that the Potala Palace has only one bathroom, located on the right side of the White Palace Square … although it is said to be the most beautiful restroom on Earth, filled with sunlight and good thoughts.\</item>
        <item>\Though pyramids were built from the beginning of the Old Kingdom to the close of the Ptolemaic dynasty, the really big heaps of stone along the Nile were piled up commencing in the late third dynasty and continuing through the sixth (roughly 500 years). The Great Pyramid of Giza that is virtually synonymous with the “glory”  of ancient Egypt went up around 2560 BC to serve as the tomb of Pharaoh Khufu (who is unremarkable for anything else save the length of his reign).\n\nIt is considered one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World. Built by tens of thousands of workers, including skilled masons, and covered with “casing stones” (slabs of polished limestone), the Pyramids of Giza were a testament to Egypt’s power and the natives’ conviction of the afterlife – at least for the elite. To date, some 135 pyramids have been found in what was once the greatest empire in the world.\</item>
        <item>\The large, dramatically colored cathedral near Moscow’s Moskva River officially bore the name “Cathedral of the Intercession of the Virgin by the Moat,” but most people referred to it as “St. Basil’s.” Also, the shorter name fits better on maps. Ivan the Terrible commissioned its construction in 1555 to commemorate victories achieved during his reign.\n\nDespite Ivan’s namesake, the cathedral turned out to be anything but terrible. The cathedral is reminiscent of a Russian nesting doll, consisting of eight separate clustered churches rather than a single one. Though St. Basil’s was originally a drab white, it received a fresh coat of bold, patterned paint in 1860 that has defined it since.\</item>
        <item>\The Statue of Liberty is one of the largest statues in the world. Measuring over 90 meters (300 feet) tall from the base of its pedestal, the statue is constructed of copper plating over an iron framework and weighs over 250 metric tons. Designed by French sculptor Frederic Bartholdi, the statue, with upraised torch and the broken chains of tyranny at her feet, was presented to the United States by the French government in 1886 to commemorate 100 years of American independence. The statue itself, Liberty Island, and nearby Ellis Island became a national monument in 1924. During WWI the statue was damaged when German spies blew up a nearby ammo dump. The torch has been closed for visiting by the public since.\n\nFor more than a century, the Statue of Liberty has stood at the mouth of the New York harbor. Often the first sight seen by immigrants arriving in America, Lady Liberty symbolizes the ideals of freedom upon which the United States was founded.\</item>
        <item>\A circle of fifty-ton slabs of rock, arranged in orientation to the stars and sun, Stonehenge is an observatory and temple in one. Begun in Southern England some 5000 years ago, Stonehenge was concentric circles of stones surrounded by a moat (or “henge”). After the henge was in place, about a thousand years later an inner ring of “bluestones” were set in place, followed by an outer ring of larger, upright “sarsen” stones some 500 years after that. The 80 bluestones, coming in at about four tons each, were transported from a quarry over 240 miles away; the sarsen stones were cut and transported about 20 miles to the site. However done, for whatever purpose, Stonehenge remains a “wondrous” achievement even after a few millennia.\</item>
        <item>\The construction of an enormous arts center for Sydney on Bennelong Point had been debated since the 1940s; in 1956 AD the government of New South Wales announced an open-ended competition for the design of something grand to show the world that the city really did have some taste. \n\nA Danish architect, Jørn Utzon won with his unique expressionist design, a series of precast concrete “shells,” covered with over a million white- or cream-colored tiles with interior glass curtain walls. So unique was the problematic design (Utzon had paid no heed to structural engineering) that it took sixteen years to build at a cost ten times more than estimated. But, once completed and officially dedicated by Queen Elizabeth II in October 1973, it has since become the iconic symbol of the one-time penal colony.\n\nFrom its 2,679-seat grand Concert Hall to the intimate 210-seat Utzon Room, the Opera House brings performances of all sorts down under.\</item>
        <item>\The Taj Mahal stands in Agra, India. It was built in the mid-16th century at the orders of the Mughal Emperor Shah Jahan, as a mausoleum for his wife. Acknowledged as one of the most beautiful structures in the world, the Taj Mahal is composed of rare and brilliant materials imported from across India and Asia - it is said that over 1000 elephants were employed to carry the sandstone, marble, jade, turquoise, sapphires, and other materials used in its construction.\n\nThe Taj Mahal complex covers an area of approximately 300 meters by 580 meters (1000 feet by 1900 feet) and consists of a gateway, garden, mausoleum, mosque, and guest house. The first three buildings are clad in white marble and covered with geometric patterns, while the mosque and guesthouse are built of brilliant red sandstone. The buildings are topped with magnificent onion-shaped domes and minarets.\n\nExperts have debated about what makes the Taj Mahal unique and beautiful. Some suggest that it lies in the structures\' marvelous proportions and symmetry, while others argue in favor of the way that the marble buildings interact with the light, giving the Taj Mahal ever-changing character as the sun rises and sets. Still others believe that its inherent beauty lies in its purpose - a man seeking to cast in stone his love for his departed wife.\</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="interesting_peoples">
        <item>Alexander the Great</item>
        <item>Augustus Caesar</item>
        <item>Baldwin IV</item>
        <item>Flavius Belisarius</item>
        <item>Catherine the Great</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="title_activity_art">Art</string>
    <string name="tab_text_1">ART</string>
    <string name="tab_text_2">LITERATURE</string>
    <string name="tab_text_3">MUSIC</string>

</resources>